Kerry: If I think about the young people
I support at the moment, so the three that
are in my class, I have a wide variety.
There may only be three, but
they are each individual people.
So one young person, if it's
verbal instruction needs the
visual support to go along with it.
And if there's any verbal, it should
be a maximum of three words at a time.
And then at least 30 seconds
worth of silent processing
time to go along with that.
For another young person
I support there's...
they can take on a lot
more verbal information.
In fact, they quite like the intricacies
of why they need to be doing XYZ in this
lesson, and like to know the reason behind
everything because that helps them feel
calm and centered, so they can take on
a lot of verbal information, but it has
to be relevant to that moment in time.
And then the other young person I
support, again, is okay with verbal
instruction to a two-step level.
But does like it backed up with visual
supports and again, given time to
process it and do it in their own time.
So not to be rushed through.
Zoe: Certain turns of phrase and things
like sarcasm, the child or young person
may not be able to interpret that as
sarcasm they may take it very literally.
The other thing is if you're
trying to explain something in
general is to use visual prompts.
So it makes more sense to
the child or young person.
Ellen: If I had a student that would
come into IT, if I gave them a lot
of paper tasks on their desks, they
might not know when the tasks end.
And they might look at it and think
like "that's a lot, I'm not doing that".
So the way I can make it easier is by
presenting like one page at a time.
Phil: I work with a lot of young people
who either need more time to process
verbal information and or can be
overloaded with too much verbal input.
Always remember that, you know, chances
are, they're not going to be ignoring
you if, you know, they know the process.
And that can be difficult because
some people think that, you know, the
autistic individual is being rude.
But you know, if you have that patience
and awareness, so ask a question,
count to 10, give them time to process,
ask again, reduce your language.
Zoe T: Verbal communication has
to be seen in the context of
human communication, which is all
about emotions and intentions.
And in order to help people with
autism better understand verbal
communication, that is where the
focus needs to be in my view.
So, it would be about using the
relationship between the person
with autism and the person, the
neuro-typical person, using the
relationship between those people
to help that person with autism,
without putting any pressure on them.